PABLO CARGNELUTTI SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with more than 4 years' experience working on different agile projects, including two as Scrum Master. Developed end-to-end customer support features on a Java based e-commerce platform including Salesforce integration. Improved by 70% the startup time for a desktop C# application. Implemented device profile mechanism to allow content catalog filtering. Creative problem solver and true believer in continuous learning.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer Intel March 2010 – today

Digital Store Services (September 2012 – today)

- Implemented flexible integration between hybris e-commerce platform and different CRM systems (e.g. Salesforce). Implementation allowed changing the CRM system while the system was running. [Java, Spring]
- Designed and developed settings manager component which improved the continuous integration process by allowing building and testing the application for 4 different environments. [Win8, JS]
- Increased from 40% to 90% the number of testable components (through unit test) by developing a mocking strategy for WinJS components. [Win 8, JS].
- Played, in simultaneous, Scrum Master and member of the delivery team roles from the project initial stages.

Intel AppUp Center (March 2010 – August 2012)

- Implemented device profile mechanism to allow catalog filtering based on Operating Systems and form factors. [C++, C#]
- Improved application startup time by 70% parallelizing requests through a thread pool. [C#]
- Developed key features that enabled marketing team to make deals with Adobe AIR. (C#)
- Coached and mentored an intern for the development of sharing on Facebook and Twitter features. Project outcome was validated and integrated to the final product. [C++, JS, C#]
- Implemented in-app purchases feature in coordination with SDK team. [C++, REST]
- Implemented exception handling using AOP in proof of concept on experimental backend for Tizen[C#, Spring]
- Played the Scrum Master and delivery team member roles of a team of 7 during 1 ½ years.

Software Engineer, Intern

Intel

May 2009 – March 2010

Aspect Oriented Programming in .NET (May 2009 – November 2009)

• Reduced in 72% the number of lines of code (i.e. LOC) in a WCF service by applying logging and exception handling aspects as a proof of concept using PostSharp tool. [C#]

Inter-process Communication in C++ (December 2009 – March 2010)

• Improved the scalability of a message dispatching based application by Implemented an inter-process communication solution as a proof of concept using boost library. [C++]

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN) Córdoba, ARG. March 2010
- Certified ScrumMaster. Scrum Alliance. October 2012.
- SCJP, Standard Edition 5.0. Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform. April 2009.

PUBLICATIONS & AWARDS

- eXPerimenting with Evolutionary Design. Intel Agile and Lean Conferences 2013. Oregon, US. April 2013.
- AOP also in .NET. Intel Software Conferences 2010. Córdoba, ARG. September 2010.
- Intel Group Recognition Award: for designing, developing and delivering the Win8 AppUp. 2012.
- Intel Division Recognition Award: for outstanding performance and stability improvements. 2010.

LANGUAGES, SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- Java, C#, Android, JavaScript, C++, SQL, XML, REST, Spring, JUnit, Selenium.
- Object Oriented Design, Aspect Oriented Programming, Test Driven Development.
- Eclipse, Visual Studio, Atlassian tool suite.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Associate Professor at Universidad Nacional de Chilecito: Thesis advisor. 2012-today
- Associate Professor at Universidad Blas Pascal Córdoba: Android Workshop. 2012
- **Graduate Professor Assistant at** UTN Córdoba: Java workshop. Algorithms and Data Structures & Web Programming. 2007-2011.